Pamela Crawford

Front-End Web Developer
PamTCrawford@gmail.com| 310-754-5138 | Los Angeles, CA
LinkedIn: pamela-t-crawford | GitHub: pamelatcrawford

SUMMARY

Collaborative Frontend developer proficient in Python and JavaScript. Accomplished problem-solver with a unique mix of Product-Development and Event Coordination. Strong attention to detail and a passion for creativity. Excellent team player and a desire to give customers an optimal user experience.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages Python JavaScript CSS HTML	Frameworks Django Flask Express Node	Operating Systems Linux Windows
Software/Version Control	Libraries/Misc.	Methodologies/Practices
Terminal Git GitHub Vagrant	jQuery Bootstrap React SocketIO	TDD Scrum Agile RESTful

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Web Content/Product Development Manager

Hoop Body Move | Los Angeles, CA | 2013-2017

- Created, streamlined and maintained web pages using HTML, Java Script, and other similar programming
- Organized site promotions, email newsletters and online outreach campaigns that increased monthly page views by 30% for 6 consecutive months
- Improved company's competitive market position by reducing product costs and accelerating delivery of new features from 3rd party sellers

Front-End Developer / Event Coordinator

Hoopnotica | Venice, CA | 2006 – 2013

- Managed HTML/CSS, testing bug fixes and adding products weekly with Magento. Grew start-up to a million-dollar company within the 5-year goal
- Monitored SEOs and test analysis to preserve the top 3 keywords in search
- Designed intranet for client's licenses and expanded clientele from 100-800 in 18 months, raised company's revenue \$15K/month
- Coordinated fitness trainings, travel and events for 200 clients and developed manuals for yearly fitness qualifications

EDUCATION

Coding Dojo | Full-Stack Web Development August 2017 – Dec 2017 Fashion Institute of Design and Merchandising | Marketing/ Product Development